Afonso Melo

Full Stack Developer



- afonsomelo27@gmail.com
- +351914021271
- Lisbon, Portugal
- m www.linkedin.com/in/afonso-melo
- github.com/a-sfvm

Junior Full Stack Developer with an educational background of Audiovisual and Multimedia. After travelling around Australia for 2 years, where I experienced various jobs in hospitality and health care, and working for another 2 years in Art Departments for TV and Cinema back in Portugal, I decided to go on a different path. Looking for a more challenging career and following a long time interest, I deep dived into the world of Web Development with a 9 week Le Wagon bootcamp.

I plan to bring good team-work ethics and communication skills combined with great eagerness to keep learning along my journey. While working on solo projects, I am looking for a full-time job in Web Development.

</> SKILLS

Ruby on Rails • HTML • CSS •

Bootstrap • JavaScript (Vue.js) • SQL •

git and GitHub • Heroku • Figma •

Adobe Illustrator • Adobe Indesign

LANGUAGES

Portuguese • English

INTERESTS

Surfing • Travelling • Photography •

Cinema • Wood Working • Editorial Design

EDUCATION

Web Development Bootcamp

Le Wagon

Jul 2024 - Sep 2024 | Lisbon, Portugal

- 9-week full-time intensive coding Bootcamp;
- Learned HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript ES6, SQL, git, GitHub, Heroku and Ruby on Rails;
- Designed, implemented and shipped to production a clone of
- Shipped a prototype of *surfbuddy.live* ☑ app in a team of 3 in 2 weeks.

Bachelor's Degree in Audiovisual and Multimedia

Escola Superior de Comunicação Social

Sep 2014 – Jun 2019 | Lisbon, Portugal

- Audiovisual and Multimedia;
- Communication and Social Sciences;
- With one semester exchange at KEA Copenhagen School of Design and Technology.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Standby Prop and Prop Master

Plural Entertainment and SP Televisão Aug 2022 – Jun 2024 | Lisbon, Portugal

- Worked closely with directors and other departments to ensure props align with the creative vision of the show;
- Developed strong organisational skills and attention to detail by researching, sourcing, creating, and maintaining a wide range of props;
- Managed last-minute changes and urgent prop requirements in a fast-paced production environment;
- Responsible for the care and continuity supervison of the various props in a scene.

Restaurant Waiter

Rústico At Hay Shed Hill

May 2021 - Jul 2021 | Margaret River, Australia

- Provided customer service to a large number of guests daily, ensuring accuracy in order-taking;
- Balanced multiple tables, handled food and beverage orders, and managed customer requests.

Clinical Assistant

The Royal Melbourne Hospital

Mar 2020 - Mar 2021 | Melbourne, Australia

- Worked closely with doctors, nurses, and other healthcare professionals to coordinate patient care like turning and repositioning patients or critical patient transports;
- Clinical cleaning on a daily basis, setting up and testing equipment, consumable restocking and stock control;
- Assisted in resolving patient care challenges, developing resourceful problem-solving skills.